

Kennethcdlc@gmail.com

Sydney, NSW (0)





linkedin.com/in/kennethcdlc/ in



kendlcdev.netlify.app/

# KENNETH **DELA CRUZ**



## SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### **PROFILE**

Innovative software engineer passionate on problem solving and constant learning. With years of experience in electrical engineering and hospitality, I get to transfer my critical thinking, problem solving and creativity skills into the ever-changing field of software engineering.

#### SKILLS

Git/ GitHub HTML •

> CSS/ SASS • Node JS •

JavaScript • //MongoDB •

Ruby on Rails • TypeScript •

> Firebase • Ruby •

MySQL • React •

PostgreSQL • React Native •

RESTful APIs •

Netlify • Vue •

Heroku • Bootstrap •

#### **EDUCATION**

2022

Redux •

**Software Engineering Immersive** 

General Assembly

2018-2019

**Master of Project Management Graduate Certificate in Information Technology** 

Central Queensland University

2010 - 2015 **Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering Bulacan State University** 

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# SUBI | July 2022 - Present **Junior Software Engineer**

- Utilises Typescript, Node.js, React Native, Parse Platform and MongoDB in full stack mobile development.
- Designs, codes and debugs software product.
- Maintains and improves existing codebases.
- Investigates problem areas and come out with solutions.
- Works with the business to implement new product features and functionality in a fast paced agile environment.

### General Assembly | 2022 **Software Engineer**

Intensive 12 week (480+ hour) course covering fundamentals in full-stack software development.

• Project 3: Pokemon Quizzr | Github | Live Site

Pokemon Quizzr is a web application that features a pokedex, "who's that pokemon" game, and leaderboard. ReactJS, Firebase, and PokemonAPI was utilised to build this fun full stack project.

• Project 2: Expense Trackr | Github | Live Site

Expense Trackr application that helps you to organize your finances keeping track of all your expenses and incomes. React JS was utilised to build the frontend and Ruby on Rails for the backend.

• Project 1: Manga-shoppu | Github | Live Site

Manga-shoppu is an e-commerce web application made using Ruby on Rails. Admin users can add and edit product details. While users can add products to their carts, have a subtotal and total costs on their cart and checkout.

Project 0: Tic Tac Toe | Github | Live Site

Utilised Javascript, CSS, HTML and jQuery to make a fun TicTacToe game project that lets you play 1v1 and demonstrates a nice responsive UI.



Kennethcdlc@gmail.com







linkedin.com/in/kennethcdlc/ in



kendlcdev.netlify.app/





# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

# **Professional Electrical Engineer**

**Engineers Australia** 

# Registered **Electrical Engineer**

Philippine Professional **Regulation Commission** 

#### **VOLUNTEER**

#### 2022 **Mentor**

Software Engineering **Immersive** General Assembly

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Canva | 2019-2022

#### **Junior Chef**

- Utilised Stakeholder management and communication skills to ensure a positive customer experience.
- Executed problem solving skills to maximize resources to deliver to strict timelines.

# **Pyramids Render Stars | 2019**

#### **Quantity Surveyor**

- Produced, measured and rated cost plans, bill of quantities and contract documentation
- Measured and costed variations in detail and accurately.
- Conducted site visits to assure estimates according to architectural plans.

#### SFA Semicon | 2017

#### **Utility Engineer**

- Executed preventive, predictive & corrective utility
- maintenance.
- Projected factory utilities expenses. Ensured utility equipment operation reliablity accross production facilities.

#### **Dream Makers Construction | 2015-2017**

#### **Field Electrical Engineer**

- Managed costs and resources to meet construction budget.
- Designed revisions and additional works using AutoCAD.
- Identified labour and material cost revisions on electrical works.